Finding aid for the Paul Monette papers, 1945-1995 LSC.1707
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Writings
  - Subseries 4.1: Poetry
    - No Witnesses / Getting On: Getting On, Palm Sunday, San Juan, other early poems, etc. (?)., Beginning 1970s; 22 leaves total typescript (primarily photocopy). (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Another copy kept by PM in red plastic folder. Deering Mansion (1 leaf typescript).
      Waiting to Die (1988) removed to Box 19 folder 22.
    - No Witnesses / Musical Comedy: Musical comedy / To Cesar., n.d.; [1 (epigraph)], 8, 14, 6, [7] leaves. Typescript [1] and holograph. 7 unnumbered leaves are marked: B [black ink], C [red], A-C [blue], unmarked (not carnal), and A [black ink]. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - No Witnesses / Musical Comedy: Corrected version., n.d.; 15 leaves. Typescript with minor holograph corrections. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      Numbered to 9 in typescript, thereafter in PM's hand.
    - No Witnesses / Musical Comedy: Drafts, evidently removed when previous material corrected. Pages begin: I mention the Indian ..., It started with ..., We slowed and slowed ..., [3] leaves. Typescript and holograph. Typescript (1) and holograph (2-3). (Box 10, Folder 13)
      Continued next folder.
    - No Witnesses / Musical Comedy: Drafts., n.d.; [2] leaves. Typescript. (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Evidently removed when previous material corrected. Pages begin: This place is not a valley (corrected to: L.A., whatever else, is the Wild West), to pass from cloud to cloud ...
    - No Witnesses / This Spring: Beginning: The lilacs say, write about us ..., n.d.; 1 leaf. Holograph on lined paper. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      No poem this title in volume No Witnesses. Never published.
    - No Witnesses / The Wedding Letter: The Wedding Letter., n.d.; [10] leaves. Typescript and holograph. Numbered [1], 2-9 [with a 3A], unnumbered or repeated numbers in next folder. Published Poetry ca. 1974-1975 [per PM]. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - No Witnesses / The Wedding Letter: Withdrawn leaves(?)., n.d.; [5] leaves. Holograph. (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Unnumbered: to light, A: I would take naps ..., B: And when, one summer day, ..., C: a piece of gingerbread, D: Every child ... [crossed out] (Continued in next folder).
    - No Witnesses / The Wedding Letter: Withdrawn leaves(?)., n.d.; [3] leaves. Holograph on lined paper. (Box 10, Folder 18)
      6 (blue ink): Everyone is / specially scarred ..., 7 (green ink): All we ask is / That you get us the ground to bless, [numbered:] E (green ink, or 7, blue ink): This is the key passage - We want you to marry.
    - No Witnesses / No Witnesses [Individual Poem]: No Witnesses., 18 leaves. Holograph. Numbered by PM in green, red, black, and blue ink. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - No Witnesses / No Witnesses [Individual Poem]: Withdrawn leaves(?)., [4] leaves. Typescript ([1]) and holograph. (Box 10, Folder 20)
      As follows: turned laughing, I couldn't halt the plans, I was through (inserted above: I couldn't halt the plans [another leaf]), Now, kiss me. ... (Continued next folder).
    - No Witnesses / No Witnesses [Individual Poem]: Withdrawn leaves(?)., [2] leaves. Typescript ([1]) and holograph ([2]). (Box 10, Folder 21)
      As follows: I wish, she says, a quatrefoil tattoo ..., (and perfectly erect) ... Let me explain: wasted on time, ...
    - No Witnesses / Old Friends: Old Friends., 4 leaves. Typescript ([1]) and 2 and holograph (unnumbered and 3). (Box 10, Folder 22)
      Unnumbered leaf: Is it the boy? No poem this title in No Witnesses volume. Never published [per PM].
    - No Witnesses / The Oasis Wish: The Blind Man [?] and The Oasis Wish. Drafts in spiral binder. Domestic notes in later leaves: Leave me the car key ... (Box 10, Folder 23)
      Binder, [4] leaves (one loose from binder) seem to be poem drafts.
      Filed in Poems / Drafts folder which includes manuscript of No Witnesses. This poem does not appear in the volume No Witnesses. Never published [PM].
    - No Witnesses [Individual Poem]: Letter from Louis Untermeyer., April 11, 1977.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. On notepaper: from the desk of Louis Untermeyer .... (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Bones and Jewels: Award. Letter from Eleanor W. Shakin, executive director, Coordinating Council of Literary Magazines., 1977 May 10. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      Poem published in Shenandoah. Collected in No Witnesses.
    - Bones and Jewels: Occidental Poets: 10., ca. May 15, 1978.; 1 printed leaf signed by PM. (Box 36, Folder 5)
      Quote: [from No Witnesses]: We were / a self-contained erotic joke, because / the great are furious with the great, ...
    - Changing Places: In: Southwest Review., Spring 1980.; p.176. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Changing Places: Award from Southwest Review., ca. 1980. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - No Witnesses: Manuscript. [date collected and published by Avon]., 1973-1975, 1981; Typescript (photocopies) in binder. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - No Witnesses: Publicity., n.d. / v.d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - No Witnesses: Reviews., n.d. / v.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - The Carol Poems: Manuscript Material: Cf. Borrowed Time., 1985-1986.; 90 leaves total. Primarily typescripts, extensive holograph corrections. (Box 16, Folder 7)
      PM: 1st draft worksheets for Love Alone & Poems to Carol (1985-86).
    - Poems, Manuscript Material, 1985-1986, 29 leaves total. Typescripts [lacking corrections]. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Copies of The Bee-Eater, Buckley, The Supreme Pork, etc., 49 leaves total. Typescript (?) and photocopies, no corrections. (Box 49, Folder 18)
      These seem to be extra copies made for various publishing purposes. Cf. New Poems (1987-1993) in West of Yesterday, East of Summer.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog [published 1988]: Letters from Betty [Berzon?] and David [Schorr] after reading drafts., 1987 and n.d.; 3 items, 5 pieces. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      1987 June 26 [postmark and n.d. (Berzon), n.d. (Schorr). Schorr also seemingly reading poems before publication.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letter from Arthur [Vogelsgang?] (American Poetry Review)., June 10, 1987.; 1 leaf. Holograph, signed. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: In: Christopher Street. Issue 119., c. 1988. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letter from Charles Corcoran., n.d.; 1 leaf (recto and verso). Holograph, signed. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letters rejecting publication of individual poems., February 20 and March 3, 1987.; 2 items, 3 pieces. (Box 17, Folder 7)
      From Mark Thompson (The Advocate) and [illegible signature] (Southwest Review).
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letters of appreciation from friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Reviews., n.d. / v.d.; Primarily photocopies. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letter from Rudy Kikel about reprinting No Goodbyes., 1987 January 29.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      First printed in Bay Windows, Kikel is writing to ask permission to print in Boston Bisexual Men's Network Newsletter.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letter from Mass Benefit: a performance of Bach's Mass in B minor for AIDS care and education (John O'Brien)., March 28, 1988, enclosure date March 18.; Typed, signed. 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      About including a statement and poem in the program booklet.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letters from Greg Myers., August 19, 1988 and August 8, 1990.; 2 leaves. Typed, signed. (Box 17, Folder 12)
      About adapting poem for a dance. Also: announcement for performance of dance.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Musical setting., August 18, 1988 (postmark); November 11, 1988; April 22, 1989; May 23, 1990.; [5 leaves total] (letters). Holograph and typed, signed and 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 17, Folder 13)
      Letters from Ned Rorem about setting Here, and various productions of the setting. Includes letter from Sylvia Goldstein (Boosey & Hawkes) about the setting: August 23, 1988.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Love Alone. For men's chorus and piano (four hands). Music by Ned Rorem. Poem [Here] by Paul Monette. NR's note at end: New York City, 1988. November 1-9, 1988.; 13pp. [4 folded leaves]. Holograph score (photocopy). (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Ned Rorem. Love Alone, Men's Chorus and Piano Four Hands. Poem by Paul Monette. No place, Boosey & Hawkes., c. 1989. (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Contains brief description from NR, stating first performed in New York, first week of November 1988.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Love Alone., June 1989. (Box 17, Folder 16)
      Program for The New York City Gay Men's Chorus [world premiere of Rorem's setting of Here].
      Kept in Louis Sherry Box.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Love Alone., 1990. (Box 17, Folder 17)
      Program for The Gay Men's Chorus of Los Angeles [California premiere of Rorem's setting of Here].
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letters received., March 20, 1990; August 7, 1992. (Box 17, Folder 18)
      Peter Schellin, poet and chorus singer(?), Jon Bailey, conductor Los Angeles Gay Men's Chorus performance of Rorem's Here [also Halfway Home fan letter].
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Mention and review., April 10 and May 2, 1990. (Box 17, Folder 19)
      Gay Men's Chorus of Los Angeles performance of Rorem setting.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Performance of Rorem's Here at Tanglewood Music Festival., August 24, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 20)
      Letter from Cornelia Fitts, program, program notes, and review of performance in Berkshire Eagle. Letter from Dave Drake Beauvais and program.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Performance of Ned Rorem's setting. Review., October 28, 1993.; Clipping. (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Performance of Ned Rorem's setting. Program., 1993. (Box 17, Folder 22)
      With holograph note from NR: Dearest Paul - Every place this piece is sung, the audience dissolves. It's the words, only the words - ....
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Honors: First Words Project for AIDS dinner., March 23, 1989. (Box 17, Folder 23)
      Clipping about dinner. Love Alone won for best poetry / fiction.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Honors: First Words Project for AIDS dinner(?)., n.d.; 1 video cassette (VHS). (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Reading announcement., December 2, 1990.; 1 folded leaf. Printed(?). (Box 17, Folder 24)
      Poetry Center [New York?], benefit reading in support of artistic freedom.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letter from Jeffrey David Brody. Also: JDB resume., 1991 October 2.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Elegies for Rog: Song-cycle for Baritone and Large Orchestra, by Jeffrey Brody. To Paul Monette. Vocal score. Piano reduction by the composer. New York City. - Boston., 1991-1992. October 30, 1991 February 23, 1992.; [vi], 82 pp. Blue print. Inscribed on title page: For Paul from Jeff, Boston, III 26 92. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: ... the wisest and justest and best ..., 1 leaf. Holograph(?). (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Last page of the score by JDB. Lines are from RH's gravestone.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Elegies for Rog [JRB setting]., n.d..; 1 leaf. Printed(?). (Box 17, Folder 26)
      The poems set were: Here, No Goodbyes, Gardenias, Half Life. Flier / program for performance of Elegies for Rog, Harvard Musical Association, June 15, 1992. Brian Davis, baritone. Jeffrey Brody, pianist.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letters from Jeffrey Brody., February 27, March 26, June 2, October 2 and December 1, 1992.; 4 items, 5 pieces. Typed, signed. (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Correspondence re Jeffrey Brody's songs., December 17, 1993; April-September 1994; February 2, 1995. (Box 17, Folder 28)
      Letters from Brody and business manager. Includes press release and program from premiere, and review of Indiana concert in 1995 [Review from DL].
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Performance of Jeffrey Brody settings. introduction, Here, Gardenias, etc., June 16, 1992.; Cassette recording. (Box 51, Folder 8)
      [Also described in sequence with Box 51]
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: All There Is Is Love, music by Roger Bourland, words by Paul Monette [TTBB]., c. 1993.; 5 leaves. Printed(?). (Box 17, Folder 29)
      Dedicated to the Gay Men's Chorus. Text adapted from Preface to Love Alone, beginning: The story that endlessly eludes the decorum of the press ....
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: All There Is Is Love, setting by Roger Bourland., April 3-4, 1993; Spring 1994.; Program and magazine. (Box 17, Folder 30)
      Program is signed by RB. Portrait of PM, RB, and Jon Bailey on cover of Choruspondence, The Quarterly Magazine of GMCLA.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: All There Is Is Love. (?)., 1993; [11] leaves. Holograph (photocopy). (Box 17, Folder 31)
      For baritone solo, small chorus, and large chorus. Words by Paul Monette. Music by Gary Bachlund.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: Letter from Gary Bachlund. Also: resume. About setting a version of Preface and part of Here., March 16, 1993.; Typed, signed (Fax). (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: Anthology: Confronting AIDS Through Literature. Letter from Judith Pastore, ed., January 8, 1993. (Box 17, Folder 33)
      Sending proofs.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: Flier for reading, Highways., n.d.; 1 leaf. (Box 17, Folder 34)
      Paul Monette ... will read from his poetry and new political writings.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: Letter from Robert Maggio to PM., n.d.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 17, Folder 35)
      Mentions having just returned from your reading at the U. Of Penn and wanting to set some poems to music.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: Letter from Richard Link., September 30, 1994. (Box 17, Folder 36)
      Asking to set Here to music.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog / Preface: David Cohen performs poems., 1994. (Box 17, Folder 37)
      Letter and newspaper article about Cohen's reading of poems from Love Alone.
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1987 and n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from: Larry Kramer, Ethan Mordden (?).
    - Love Alone: 18 Elegies for Rog: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - To GB from Tuscany: Letter from Larry Goldstein. Michigan Quarterly Review. Date of poem, 1987 per PM., December 7, 1987.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - To GB from Tuscany: Printer's proof and letter from Larry Goldstein. Published in issue of Michigan Quarterly Review., n.d. Fall 1988; 3 leaves (photocopy). Letter typed, signed, with holograph additions. (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - To GB from Tuscany: Postcard of appreciation from Ruth Weisberg. [postmark illegible]., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - To GB from Tuscany: Letters received from John De Marzo., March, May and October-November 1994. (Box 19, Folder 21)
      re Setting to music and recording it. Also Gardenias, The Girl in the Field (from Carpenter at the Asylum), House on Kings Road, Widower, Contexts.
    - Waiting to Die: Drafts. (?)., 1988; 4 leaves total. Typescript (holograph corrections) and photocopy. Typescript (photocopy) makes corrections from typescript. (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Waiting to Die: Memorial service program for Robert David Almgren., June 12, 1988. (Box 19, Folder 23)
      Contains printing of poem dedicated to Almgren.
    - Ed Dying: In: Christopher Street. Issue 123. CS Poetry., c. 1988.; Clipping. (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Ed Dying: Conference (Miami)., November 18, 1989.; Clipping. (Box 19, Folder 25)
      Conference organized by John Preston. Also: Edmund White, Andrew Holleran .... Poem republished Tribes vol.1 no.2 (Spring 1990).
    - Ed Dying: In: Tribes. vol.1 no.2. [from DL]., Spring 1990 (Box 19, Folder 26)
      Note: publicity airs [sic?] on the right side ...
    - Buckley: Letter from Lev Raphael., December 1988.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 19, Folder 27)
      Mentions poem's publication in Out / Look.
    - Buckley: Reviews., August 1, 1989 and n.d.; Clippings. (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Buckley: Mention. In Newsday., August 4, 1989.; Clipping (photocopy). (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Stephen at the FDA: Stephen at the FDA., [n.d.]. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Written after Stephen Kolzak's protest at Federal Drug Administration building (Alexandria, Virginia?).
      For draft(?) (holograph) see Box 20 folder 2.
    - Stephen at the FDA: In: Frontiers. vol.9 issue 15., November 23, 1990 [written 1988].; p.27. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Poetry: Come Spring: Extra copies., 1992 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      1 copy cataloged for Special Collections.
    - "Committing to Memory," "Frontiers" Magazine, 1993 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - West of Yesterday East of Summer: New and Selected Poems (1973-1993) [c. 1994]: Gathering of introduction, copies of poems, with title page, dedication page, etc. for this assembly of works., Largely unnumbered, 126 leaves total. Typescript (photocopy) and photocopies from various printings. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - West of Yesterday East of Summer: New and Selected Poems (1973-1993): Reviews., n.d. / v.d.; Clippings. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - West of Yesterday East of Summer: New and Selected Poems (1973-1993) / Dr. Burnout, To GB from Tuscany: Musical adaptions, composer / performer not indentified., Cassette recording. (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous: Manuscript Materials (?): Copies of The Bee-Eater, Buckley, The Supreme Pork, etc., n.d.; 49 leaves total. Typescript (?) and photocopies, no corrections. (Box 49, Folder 18)
      These seem to be extra copies made for various publishing purposes. Cf. New Poems (1987-1993) in West of Yesterday, ....
    - The Bee-Eater: Letters from Wendy Lesser, ed. The Threepenny Review., March 2 and March 30, 1994.; 1 leaf each. Typescript, signed. Each an oblong card. (Box 47, Folder 11)
      First letter mentions PM's quote, evidently about the Review, and WL's review of Borrowed Time. Second letter gives publishing details of the poem.
    - The Bee-Eater: In: The Threepenny Review., Fall 1994.; [Page unknown] Clipping. (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - West of Yesterday East of Summer: Letters of Appreciation: From friends., 1994. (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Letters from: Sascha Bittner, Otis Charles, Cornelia Fitts.
    - West of Yesterday East of Summer: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - "West of Yesterday, East of Tomorrow": Galley, 1994 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - West Running Brook: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1988. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      Includes letter from: Jim _____.
  - Subseries 4.2: Fiction
    - Gifted Brick Day: Miscellaneous pages. [date supplied by PM]., 1967-1968; [41] leaves. Typescript. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Present: 57, 82-97, unnumbered leaf [Chapter Four], 98-118, 122, 127. PM: Stuff / Other Dreams: revised typescript.
    - Gifted Brick Day: Novel., n.d.; 53pp. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Chapter 1 Transcript of rough draft revised. Also excerpts from Chapter 2 and Chapter 4.
    - Gifted Brick Day: Chapter 2: 34-68. Also includes Chapter 1: 1-30., n.d.; 66pp. typescript. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Gifted Brick Day: Chapter 3: 98-131., n.d.; 35 leaves typescript. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Gifted Brick Day: Chapter 2 & 4. Transcript of rough draft revised., n.d.; 57pp. typescript and holograph with notecards. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Gifted Brick Day: Stuff / Other Dreams: Paul's (Bart's) and Jane's Chapters Rough D., 28 holograph leaves in yellow notebook. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Gifted Brick Day: Gifted Brick Day and Winters We Went Away., Typescripts. (Box 9, Folder 13)
      51pp. typescript of Gifted Brick Day. 15pp. typescript. 6 typescript (Gifted Brick Day).
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll [Published in 1978]: Last page. (Date per PM)., 1975; 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Reviews., 1978 and n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Clippings, photocopies, and issue of GPU News (March 1978).
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Mentions. Reading announcement, lack of promotion of the book, etc., July 12, 1978; September 6, 1984 and n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      In Bay Area Reporter: Mrs. Carroll on list of gay books banned in England. Also clipping: Monette Claims Bias [in promotion of book], publ. unknown.
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Interviews., ca. 1978-1979. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      With Craig Rowland in Gay Community News, others in: In Touch, After Dark, etc.
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll. Also letter from David [Mettee?]., May 18, 1994. May 26, 1994.; 96 leaves. Typescript(?) (photocopy) and holograph letter. (Box 47, Folder 23)
      A Musical based on the novel ... by Paul Monette. Book by Martin Casella, lyrics by Georgia Holof, music by David Mettee
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Recording of musical adaption. (?)., 1994; 1 cassette tape. (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll: Musical adaption, Cassette tape (Box 51, Folder 10)
      [Also described in record with Box 47]
    - The Gold Diggers [Published March 1979]: Notes, drafts., ca. 1978.; 10 leaves total. Holograph. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Some leaves from spiral notebook. Some leaves numbered consecutively. Some scenes have characters: Nick, Rita....etc.
    - The Gold Diggers: Outline., ca. 1978 [per PM].; [6] leaves. Holograph. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - The Gold Diggers: First draft., ca. 1978.; 141 leaves total. Primarily holograph. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - The Gold Diggers: Gold Diggers. Parts one and two. In: Blueboy., March-April 1979. (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Part one March, pp.34-35, 17-18, 21, 28.
      Part two April, pp.19-22, 24-25, 29.
    - The Gold Diggers: Editor's letters, publicity, etc., 1979. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      Some with enclosures: sample cover illustration, review of gay literature (George Whitmore about Taking Care of Mrs. Carroll, but sent 1979?), etc.
    - The Gold Diggers: Letter received., January 26, 1979. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - The Gold Diggers: Interviews. In: The Advocate, Issue 274, (also review)., August 1979. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Here: Follies [section of unnamed paper, or is name of paper?].
      Filed in Box 40 (OVERSIZE)
    - The Gold Diggers: Interviews. In: The Advocate, Issue 274, (also review)., 1979 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - The Gold Diggers: Re-Publication Material: Letter from Sasha Alyson., June 17, 1987.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - The Gold Diggers: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1988, 1994. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from: Lev Raphael (1988), Paul Reed (1994).
    - The Long Shot [First Printing, March 1981]: Research Material (?): Letters, postcards, clippings., Late 1970s. (Box 11, Folder 22)
      Letters from Ed ___, from Cesar [Albini], postcards of Santa Barbara, clippings from Blueboy.
    - The Long Shot: Notes., Late 1970s.; 9 leaves total. Holograph. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - The Long Shot: Chapters 1 & 2., n.d.; 77 leaves total. (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Novel #3 up through pp.98,99.
    - The Long Shot: Research Material (?): Clippings., n.d. / v.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Filed with following draft.
    - The Long Shot: PM: 6 / 20-9 / 11 into / almost through Chapter 5., n.d.; 72 leaves total. Primarily holograph. (Box 12, Folder 2)